<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xia Shen</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Xia Shen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zn-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlation analysis in R</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-09/correlation-analysis-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-09/correlation-analysis-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Correlation analysis In correlation analysis, we estimate a sample correlation coefficient, more specifically the Pearson Product Moment correlation coefficient. The sample correlation coefficient, denoted r, ranges between -1 and +1 and quantifies the direction and strength of the linear association between the two variables.
The correlation between two variables can be positive or negative.The sign of the correlation coefficient indicates the direction of the association. The magnitude of the correlation coefficient indicates the strength of the association.
For example, a correlation of r = 0.9 suggests a strong, positive association between two variables, whereas a correlation of r = -0.2 suggest a weak, negative association. A correlation close to zero suggests no linear association between two continuous variables.
From –Boston University School of Public Health
 correlation plot head(mtcars) ## mpg cyl disp hp drat wt qsec vs am gear carb ## Mazda RX4 21.0 6 160 110 3.90 2.620 16.46 0 1 4 4 ## Mazda RX4 Wag 21.0 6 160 110 3.90 2.875 17.02 0 1 4 4 ## Datsun 710 22.8 4 108 93 3.85 2.320 18.61 1 1 4 1 ## Hornet 4 Drive 21.4 6 258 110 3.08 3.215 19.44 1 0 3 1 ## Hornet Sportabout 18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/2019-08/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/2019-08/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Academic interest I am now a Ph.D. candidate student in SIBS, Chinese Academy of Sciences (CAS). I am broadly interested in Metabolomics, Biostatictics, Systems biology and Bioinformatics. My research interest is the development of bioinformatic algorithms and tools for analyzing metabolomics data as well as its application in discovering new biomarkers related to human diseases. Personal interest Actually，I am a bboy who is undertaking PhD study, I like breaking dance and play badminton sometimes。 实际上我是个正在读博的bboy，但是现在很久都跳不上一次舞了，各种原因吧，心里很想像大学时代那样，每天晚上都去跳舞，完了洗个澡，特别舒服，强身健体。现在每天“下班”都很累，锻炼的机会也好少了。偶尔去打打羽毛球，还经常</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Somewhere the sun is shining</title>
      <link>/moment/2019-08/moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/moment/2019-08/moment/</guid>
      <description>Somewhere the sun is shining, and the clouds are not in sight, 某处阳光正好， 天空看不见白云飘摇。 Somewhere some’s laughing, and talking about what might. 某处有人在笑， 谈论着今后的生活。 What might have been another year, for us to spend together. 来年会是什么样子， 让我们一起度过。 What might have been another time, that I could cherish forever. 下次会是什麽样子， 让我能永远珍惜。 Somewhere two people laugh and joke, and carry on all day. 某处两人正在谈笑， 一整天笑弯了腰。 Talk about their past and future, In an extraordinary way. 谈论他们的过去和未来， 是多么非凡精彩。 They talk about the last few years, And how they made a bond. 他们谈论刚过去的岁月， 他们是如何</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build personal blog with hugo and rmarkdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-08/build-personal-blog-with-hugo-and-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-08/build-personal-blog-with-hugo-and-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>缘起 最近根据网上的教程摸索搭建了自己个人网站，为了多熟悉一下markdown和宣传自己，哈哈哈。下面就把本次建站的过程做一个比较详细的记录，因为这个过程还是比较艰辛的，各种试错改bug，不过看到网站建起来就有一丢丢成就感埋没了这些艰辛。活着就是折腾 1:本地建站 R和Rstudio以及相关包(blogdown)的安装这里就不赘述了。 rstudio 配置 安装好上述软件和包后，需要对rstudio进行简单配置： Tools -&amp;gt; Global Options</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>